Hello, my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course.
So an exercise number of 52, we are asked to write a function to remove duplicates from the link,
at least consider a linked list that contains nodes.
And inside this note, there are a value that may be they are kids like five and five, or if we have
a link, at least if we run our current linked list that we have created before.
In the previous exercises, we have four, one, five and three.
I will add in you not that will contain number five.
So for that, I will go to the main.
I would create a new node here or already we can like call at Append.
Then you not.
I will copy and paste this append no equal to five.
That's right, and same.
And here we go, we have four, one, five, three and five.
Our mission to remove the duplicates from the link at last.
OK.
So please go back to the lecture in order to understand what is the concept of this by using an animation?
And if you are ready, so let's go and make our new method.
So I will create public void and remove duplicates.
Method.
It will not take any perimeter and it will not return.
Anything goes its mission to remove the duplicates and go through their elements and depart it in one,
not one, equal to none.
I will create also another nod.
Note No.
Two equal to no.
Another No.
Not the equal to none,
and I will refer to not.
The one equal to the hat.
OK, so not one will be.
No one will be referring to the hat.
No, I will create a loop that will go through every element and pick one elements one by one silk bag.
This is the first step.
One big elements, one by one.
So while not one does not equal to none and not to the next does not equal to none.
So I am comparing the current state, the current not and the next not.
If it does not equal to none, then not to equal to not one.
OK, now inside this loop, I will create a nested loop that will compare to the pick element with the
rest of that element.
So this is the trick behind this question.
So comparing the big cat element with that rest, with the rest of the animals
elements, OK?
While
they're not to, the next does not equal to null if there is no stop between and then reach the end
of the list, check the third step.
Check if duplicates and delete it.
OK, if not one dog data equal equal to not to the next.
The data, then
then.
This sequence of step is very important.
So not to the next equal to nod to the next door.
Next, we are referring to the next system
the G.
C.
OK.
Now, let's again make an else statement.
This is tricky because part the chin or the not to not to the equal, not to equal
now to the next.
OK.
It's very simple now.
Here we need to move the cursor to make not to not one sort of equals to not one dot the next, I'm
moving the node one.
This is for the outer look so that the outer loop will go through every time and make not to equal to
not one.
And go through this loop.
And then it will not one it will increase the pointer and move the pointer from it, from the current
state and move it to the next and.
OK, so not one becomes the next, not every time this loop will go a direction and the while loop that's
nested there, while loop, it will works with every element and compare it with the rest of that.
OK.
So let's go and test this by making.
Calling.
But first of all, let me again check the list, we have four one five three five.
We expect remove to remove the fact this is exercise.
Fifty two in more than double the rate gates.
Then make list the remove the public airwaves and then system that print the power with print we call
linked list print again, the list print the list.
We have created this method in that first exercise and I think at least that's redundancy.
We have four one five three five.
Then after that inspection, exception failed to read next.
Not is not next.
Not.
Is at two hundred not two, OK?
It would be dot dot, not one.
And here we go.
This is the list before removing the duplicates for one five three five.
And this is the list after removing duplicates for one, five and three.
We have removed the last one, which is five, which is the duplicate of five.
OK.
And there we go.
We have created these exercises and we have created these methods throughout this exercise.
We will continue with the reverse and link list and rotate and link at and by that week we can or we
covered the all link.